Guide to the Sylvester Manor Archive 1649-1996 MSS 208
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Record Group IV: Horsford Family
  - Series I: General Horsford Materials
    - Subseries 1: Correspondence
      - Mary Leila "Lilian" Horsford to sister, undated (Box 109, Folder 38)
      - Phoebe Horsford to Cornelia and Lilian Horsford, 1897 (Box 110, Folder 1)
      - Phoebe Horsford to Kate and Cornelia Horsford, 1894, undated (Box 110, Folder 2)
      - Phoebe Horsford to Lilian and Kate Horsford, 1886, undated (Box 110, Folder 3)
      - Phoebe Horsford to daughters, 1886-1894, undated (Box 110, Folder 4)
      - Phoebe Horsford to daughters 1 of 3, undated (Box 110, Folder 5)
      - Phoebe Horsford to daughters 2 of 3, undated (Box 110, Folder 6)
      - Phoebe Horsford to daughters 3 of 3, undated (Box 110, Folder 7)
      - to Miss Horsford, 1891 (Box 110, Folder 8)
      - Julia Ann to Grandma (?), undated (Box 110, Folder 9)
      - Sarah Orne Jewett and Annie Fields to Kate Horsford and Cornelia Horsford, 1906 (Box 110, Folder 10)
      - J.R.L. to Miss Horsford, undated (Box 110, Folder 11)
      - G.M. Lane, 1886 (Box 110, Folder 12)
      - to G.M. Lane, undated (Box 110, Folder 13)
      - Mary Catherine L'Hommedieu to granddaughters (Mary, Phoebe and Frances), undated (Box 110, Folder 14)
      - Lizzie V. Lidyard (?) to Miss Horsford, undated (Box 110, Folder 15)
      - Blank order form for Daniel Low, undated (Box 110, Folder 16)
      - Charles Merriam, Treasurer, Boston - empty envelope, undated (Box 110, Folder 17)
      - Grace Norton to Misses Horsford, 1906 (Box 110, Folder 18)
      - M. Norton and M.C. Horsford to Clarinda Thompson, undated (Box 110, Folder 19)
      - Robert and Julia Norton to Phoebe Horsford (+ Lilian, Kate and Cornelia), 1897 (Box 110, Folder 20)
      - Marianne Ogden to friends, 1889 (Box 110, Folder 21)
      - A.R.P., undated (Box 110, Folder 22)
      - J.M. Peirce to Miss Horsford, 1884 (Box 110, Folder 23)
      - Henry H. Preston, 1889 March 13 (Box 110, Folder 24)
      - to Jesse Preston from E.N. Horsford, Phoebe Horsford, Lilian Horsford, Cornelia Horsford and Kate Horsford 1 of 3, circa 1884-1889, 1925 (Box 110, Folder 25)
      - to Jesse Preston from E.N. Horsford, Phoebe Horsford, Lilian Horsford, Cornelia Horsford and Kate Horsford 2 of 3, circa 1884-1889, 1925 (Box 110, Folder 26)
      - to Jesse Preston from E.N. Horsford, Phoebe Horsford, Lilian Horsford, Cornelia Horsford and Kate Horsford 3 of 3, circa 1884-1889, 1925 (Box 110, Folder 27)
      - Bertha Printice to ?, 1891 (Box 110, Folder 28)
      - John W. White to Miss Horsford, 1885 (Box 110, Folder 29)
      - note to Mrs. Wyman (Morrill), undated (Box 110, Folder 30)
      - Telegrams from various 1 of 2, 1893 (Box 110, Folder 31)
      - Telegrams from various 2 of 2, 1893 (Box 110, Folder 32)
      - Unknown note, undated (Box 110, Folder 33)
      - Unknown to Horsford sisters, undated (Box 110, Folder 34)
      - Unknown to mother (Cornelia to Phoebe Horsford?), undated (Box 110, Folder 35)
    - Subseries 2: History/Genealogy Materials
      - Genealogy notes, 1841 (Box 110, Folder 36)
      - "Documents Relating to the Conveyance of Land on Long Island", 1850 (Box 110, Folder 37)
      - Biographical Notice of Nicoll H. Dering, 1868 (Box 110, Folder 38)
      - New York Genealogical and Biographical Recor d, Vol. 2, No. 1 (includes biography of Ezra L'Hommedieu, 1871 January (Box 110, Folder 39)
      - Shelter Island Board of Health, 1871 (Box 110, Folder 40)
      - Copy of "Account of sundrys taken" during Revolution (original date - 1694) - copied by Lilian Horsford, 1871 (Box 110, Folder 41)
      - Copy of receipt from Joshua Hobart (original date - 1694), 1871 (Box 110, Folder 42)
      - Copy of the register of births and deaths contained in the oldest L'Hommedieu family bible, 1884 July (Box 110, Folder 43)
      - Brief history of the L'Hommedieu family, with letter from N.C. L'Hommedieu, 1884 (Box 110, Folder 44)
      - Programs - unveiling of the monument to Nathaniel Sylvester, 1884 (Box 110, Folder 45)
      - Descent of John Nelson and of his children (unopened), 1886 (Box 110, Folder 46)
      - Suffolk County Historical Society constitution and by-laws, 1886 (Box 110, Folder 47)
      - Genealogy notes and empty envelopes ["Report of a Committee on Governor Clinton's Letters" removed to Box 24 Folder 29], circa 1886 (Box 110, Folder 48)
      - Magazine of American History Illustrated with article on Sylvester Manor by Martha J. Lamb (4 copies), 1887 (Box 111, Folder 1)
      - "Some Interesting Lines of Descent" - Horsford genealogy, 1890 (Box 111, Folder 2)
      - Putnam's Monthly Historical Magazine, Vol. I, No. 3, 1892 July (Box 111, Folder 3)
      - Horsford ancestry, 1892 (Box 111, Folder 4)
      - British Museum reading room information, 1904 (Box 111, Folder 5)
      - Reproduction of L'Hommedieu genealogy [with newspaper clipping from from], circa 1906 (Box 111, Folder 6)
      - Genealogy and historical notes (Kate?), 1907-1908 (Box 111, Folder 7)
      - Certified copy of charter of Richard Nicolls to Constant and Nathaniell Silvester (original date - 1666), 1909 (Box 111, Folder 8)
      - Transcribed copies of New York State Archives documents regarding Sylvester family (originals dated 1683 and circa 1783), 1909 (Box 111, Folder 9)
      - Certified copy of Constant Sylvester will (original date - 1696), 1909 (Box 111, Folder 10)
      - Certified copy of Peter Sylvester will (original date - 1696), 1909 (Box 111, Folder 11)
      - Certified copy of Nathaniell Sylvester II's will (original date - 1705), 1909 (Box 111, Folder 12)
      - Certified copy of Gyles Sylvester will (original date - 1706), 1909 (Box 111, Folder 13)
      - Genealogy notes made in engagement calendar, 1909 (Box 111, Folder 14)
      - Typed copy of Jonathan Havens will (original date - 1774), 1927 March 12 (Box 111, Folder 15)
      - Notice regarding records of Barbados, undated (Box 111, Folder 16)
      - Transcript of letter printed by E.N. Horsford - Ph. Schuyler to Ezra L'Hommedieu 1780, undated (Box 111, Folder 17)
      - Horsford/Norton genealogy - handwritten manuscript, pages 1-10, undated (Box 111, Folder 18)
      - Notes on L'Hommedieu, numbered page 2, undated (Box 111, Folder 19)
      - Drafts, notes and miscellaneous material for genealogical manuscript 1 of 8, undated (Box 111, Folder 20)
      - Drafts, notes and miscellaneous material for genealogical manuscript 2 of 8, undated (Box 111, Folder 21)
      - Drafts, notes and miscellaneous material for genealogical manuscript 3 of 8, undated (Box 112, Folder 1)
      - Drafts, notes and miscellaneous material for genealogical manuscript 4 of 8, undated (Box 112, Folder 2)
      - Drafts, notes and miscellaneous materials for genealogical manuscript 5 of 8, undated (Box 112, Folder 3)
      - Drafts, notes and miscellaneous materials for genealogical manuscript 6 of 8, undated (Box 112, Folder 4)
      - Drafts, notes and miscellaneous materials for genealogical manuscript 7 of 8, undated (Box 112, Folder 5)
      - Drafts, notes and miscellaneous materials for genealogical manuscript 8 of 8, undated (Box 112, Folder 6)
      - Copy - Samuel L'Hommedieu Senior ancestry, undated (Box 112, Folder 7)
      - Genealogy notes, undated (Box 112, Folder 8)
      - Handwritten copy of Nathaniell Sylvester's Will (original date - 1680), undated (Box 112, Folder 9)
      - Genealogy notes, undated (Box 112, Folder 10)
      - Manuscript - biography of Ezra L'Hommedieu, undated (Box 112, Folder 11)
      - E.N. Horsford biographical/professional information, undated (Box 112, Folder 12)
      - Copy - indenture between Ezra L'Hommedieu and Thomas Dering, undated (Box 112, Folder 13)
      - Copy of register of births and deaths from L'Hommedieu family bible, undated (Box 112, Folder 14)
      - Genealogy notes about L'Hommedieu family, undated (Box 112, Folder 15)
      - Handwritten copy of indexes of Town of Southold, including information on Sylvester family, undated (Box 112, Folder 16)
      - Genealogy notes - Van Rensslear, Havens and Van Weely familes, undated (Box 112, Folder 17)
      - Genealogy notes, undated (Box 112, Folder 18)
      - Handwritten copy of release of Giles Sylvester to claims of land (original date 1701), undated (Box 112, Folder 19)
      - Printed reproduction of land grant to Lion Gardiner for Gardiner's Island (original date - 1689), undated (Box 112, Folder 20)
      - Typed reproduction of Nathaniel Silvester's submission to the Dutch (original date 1673), undated (Box 112, Folder 21)
      - Copy of indenture - Giles Sylvester to Joshua Sylvester (original date 1694), undated (Box 112, Folder 22)
      - Copy of miscellaneous records from Barbados regarding Sylvesters (original dates circa 1645-1675), undated (Box 112, Folder 23)
      - Copy of indenture between William Nicoll and Brinley Sylvester (original date 1733), undated (Box 112, Folder 24)
      - Typed transcript of "Proceedings of the New York Provinvial Congress - June 10, 1776 - December 5, 1776" by Ezra L'Hommedieu, undated (Box 112, Folder 25)
      - Genealogical gelanings in England, by Henry F. Waters (includes Brinley and Sylvester), undated (Box 112, Folder 26)
      - Receipt for payment for Miss Horsford's washing, 1875 (Box 112, Folder 27)
      - Miss Horsford to Mrs. S.H. Raynor for flowers, 1884 July 10 (Box 112, Folder 28)
      - Decree of probate court, 1900 (Box 112, Folder 29)
      - Shelter Island tax receipts, 1905-1909 (Box 112, Folder 30)
      - Purchase order to Miss Horsford, 1909 (Box 112, Folder 31)
      - Apothecary prescriptions, 1916 (Box 112, Folder 32)
    - Subseries 3: Financial and Sylvester Manor materials
      - Shelter Island Trustees Reports 1 of 3, 1896-1916 (Box 113, Folder 1)
      - Shelter Island Trustees Reports 2 of 3, 1896-1916 (Box 113, Folder 2)
      - Shelter Island Trustees Reports 3 of 3, 1896-1916 (Box 113, Folder 3)
      - Miss Horsford's chicken account, undated (Box 113, Folder 4)
      - Small account book, undated (Box 113, Folder 5)
      - List of brushes, etc, undated (Box 113, Folder 6)
      - Accounting lists, undated (Box 113, Folder 7)
      - Account, undated (Box 113, Folder 8)
      - Bills/receipts for Miss Horsford's washing, undated (Box 113, Folder 9)
      - Property notes, undated (Box 113, Folder 10)
      - Inventory of items in West Room cupboard, undated (Box 113, Folder 11)
      - Inventories - Books in bookcases, pictures on the walls, photos, undated (Box 113, Folder 12)
      - Visits book and address book, undated (Box 113, Folder 13)
    - Subseries 4: Memorial Programs
      - Program for memorial window dedication for Mary L'Hommedieu Gardiner Horsford 1 of 3, 1872 (Box 113, Folder 14)
      - Program for memorial window dedication for Mary L'Hommedieu Gardiner Horsford 2 of 3, 1872 (Box 113, Folder 15)
      - Program for memorial window dedication for Mary L'Hommedieu Gardiner Horsford 3 of 3, 1872 (Box 113, Folder 16)
      - Eben Norton Horsford memorial service at Wellesley College, 1893 January 26 (Box 113, Folder 17)
      - Phoebe Gardiner Horsford's obituary clipping, 1903 (Box 113, Folder 18)
      - Bound copy - "In Memoriam - Eben Norton Horsford" service at Shepard Memorial Church, 1893 (Box 113, Folder 19)
    - Subseries 5: Newspapers and Scrapbooks
      - Newspapers about slaughterhouse complaints including Boston Advertiser, 1872-1873 (Box 113, Folder 20)
        Some clippings removed to oversize materials
      - Scrapbook of clippings - E.N. Horsford obituaries and misc, 1891, 1893, undated (Box 113, Folder 21)
      - Clippings from inside cover of "Scrapbook of clippings - E.N. Horsford obituaries and misc", 1885-1893, undated (Box 114, Folder 1)
      - Scrapbook of clippings - Sylvester Monument, E.N. Horsford's death, 1884-1895, undated (Box 114, Folder 2)
      - Obituary of Sarah Orne Jewett - fragments, 1909 (Box 114, Folder 3)
      - Newspaper clippings - obituaries for Dr. Braden Kyle and prescription, 1916 (Box 114, Folder 4)
      - Newspaper fragment - New York Times "Building Grafters to Get Jail Terms", circa 1921 (Box 114, Folder 5)
      - Suffolk Times "Shelter Island Armistice Day" and fragments, 1922 (Box 114, Folder 6)
      - Clipping re Shelter Island, 1926 (Box 114, Folder 7)
      - Newspaper clippings from Hampton Star, unknown articles re Shelter Island history, social notes, circa 1927 (Box 114, Folder 8)
      - Newspaper clipping from Boston Post about E.N. Horsford, 1931 July 27 (Box 114, Folder 9)
      - Newspaper clipping about Gardiner's Island, undated (Box 114, Folder 10)
    - Subseries 6: Poetry and manuscripts
      - Harvard Class Day Reception (Misses Horsford), 1870 (Box 114, Folder 11)
      - Invitation to Calico Hop, 1871 Feburary 21 (Box 114, Folder 12)
      - Admission tickets, 1870-1872 (Box 114, Folder 13)
      - Text of address given on Shelter Island, circa 1872 (Box 114, Folder 14)
      - Poem "Old and Dearest", 1876 (Box 114, Folder 15)
      - "A Poetical Visit to Shelter Island by C. (P.) D., 1877 August 25 (Box 114, Folder 16)
      - Diary (Cornelia Horsford?), 1877-1885 (Box 114, Folder 17)
      - J. Rollin Tilton - private exhibition of art, 1880 (Box 114, Folder 18)
      - "The Every Day Darling" poem (Kate?), 1881 (Box 114, Folder 19)
      - Helen Hunt Jackson Manuscript and portrait [items originally framed together], 1881 (Box 114, Folder 20)
      - Poem by Prescott Evarts, 1881 (Box 114, Folder 21)
      - Poem "The Little Mosses" by Olea Bull, 1882 April 19 (Box 114, Folder 22)
      - Poems by B.R. Curtis, 1877-1882 (Box 114, Folder 23)
      - Sarah Orne Jewett poem about Shelter Island (autograph) [reverse of document signatures [?] Farmer, C.C. Fellin, Jared Sparks, Andrew Norton, 1884 (Box 114, Folder 24)
      - Poem "The Eastern Question", 1885 (Box 114, Folder 25)
      - List of houseguests at Shelter Island, circa 1885 (Box 114, Folder 26)
      - Meeting of Shakespeare Society (Welleseley), 1886 (Box 114, Folder 27)
      - Wedding invitations, 1888-1889 (Box 114, Folder 28)
      - Long Island Magazine Illustrated with article about E.N. Horsford, 1893 April (Box 114, Folder 29)
      - Untitled poems, 1867, 1894 (Box 114, Folder 30)
      - Invitation to meeting of the spirits of Patience and Grisselle Sylvester, 1895 (Box 114, Folder 31)
      - The American Anthropologist, Vol. XI, No. 1 (Horsford's acid phosphate advertisement on back cover), 1898 (Box 114, Folder 32)
      - Life Magazine, 1898 April 2 (Box 114, Folder 33)
      - Correspondents register, 1891-1899 (Box 114, Folder 34)
      - Epher Whitaker birthday invitation, 1900 (Box 114, Folder 35)
      - Greate Concere of Musick, 1901 (Box 115, Folder 1)
      - Invitation to ten, 1904 (Box 115, Folder 2)
      - Harvest festival flyer, 1907 (Box 115, Folder 3)
      - Constitution and by-laws of the Massachusetts Society of the Colonial Dames of America, 1908 (Box 115, Folder 4)
      - Poem "Sylvester Manor" by Laurette de T. Prime, 1914 July 20 (Box 115, Folder 5)
      - Poem, 1917 (Box 115, Folder 6)
      - Carnival "Souvenir" and calendar of the colonies, 1924 (Box 115, Folder 7)
      - Brief survey of the Massachusetts system of savings bank life insurance and annuities, 1936 (Box 115, Folder 8)
      - Excursions from Geneve-Lausanne by rail, boat and postal motor coach, 1938 (Box 115, Folder 9)
      - Poem (song?) "Oh Dearie Me", undated (Box 115, Folder 10)
      - Notes - "Don't Forget", undated (Box 115, Folder 11)
      - Walt Whitman poem, undated (Box 115, Folder 12)
      - "Elizabethan poets 1550-1620", undated (Box 115, Folder 13)
      - Actors and actresses and tableaux, undated (Box 115, Folder 14)
      - Description of the landscape parlor K.H. gave to C.H. (Kate Horsford to Cornelia Horsford?), undated (Box 115, Folder 15)
        Note from Augustus Fiske removed to Box 117 Folder 40
      - Obituary of Mrs. Mary Sylvester, undated (Box 115, Folder 16)
      - John Greenleaf Whittier poem "At Shelter Island 1660", undated (Box 115, Folder 17)
      - Address book, undated (Box 115, Folder 18)
      - List of plays (?), undated (Box 115, Folder 19)
      - Visit with the pope, undated (Box 115, Folder 20)
      - Poem fragment, undated (Box 115, Folder 21)
      - Draft of play about Sylvester Manor, undated (Box 115, Folder 22)
      - "The Ghost of Abbey Manor" and "The Missing Ring", undated (Box 115, Folder 23)
      - Poem draft, undated (Box 115, Folder 24)
      - Diary of events, undated (Box 115, Folder 25)
      - Poem (Dresden Gallery?), undated (Box 115, Folder 26)
      - Poems "It isn't the things you do dear" and "Blessings on this home so dear", undated (Box 115, Folder 27)
      - Poem "Roman Virgil, Thou that singest", undated (Box 115, Folder 28)
      - "Romantic" card, undated (Box 115, Folder 29)
      - Misc notes and fragments, undated (Box 115, Folder 30)
      - Poem by Julia Gardiner Tyler, undated (Box 115, Folder 31)
      - Poem "Believe me if all those endearing young charms..." (Box 115, Folder 32)
      - Stamps, undated (Box 115, Folder 33)
      - "Definitions of Civilization" from party guest (?), undated (Box 115, Folder 34)
      - "The Three Swiss Hotel - Coblenz" - ad, misc Horsford, undated (Box 115, Folder 35)
      - Misc poems and notes, undated (Box 115, Folder 36)
      - Poem "The Swamp Lyric", undated (Box 115, Folder 37)
      - Poem "Hail to the Lady of our Houses", undated (Box 115, Folder 38)
      - Poem, undated (Box 115, Folder 39)
      - Poems, undated (Box 115, Folder 40)
      - Poem "Loves Last Trubute", undated (Box 115, Folder 41)
      - "The Geizen Grade" drawing, undated (Box 115, Folder 42)
      - History and botany notes, undated (Box 115, Folder 43)
      - Documents re death of Henry F. Durant (Wellesley), undated (Box 115, Folder 44)
      - Draft of poem about Sylvester Manor, undated (Box 115, Folder 45)
      - Poem about Sylvester Manor, undated (Box 115, Folder 46)
      - Poem "John Burns of Gettysburg", undated (Box 115, Folder 47)
      - Manuscript - "Wife, children and friends" by William Robert Spencer, undated (Box 115, Folder 48)
    - Subseries 7: Gardening Materials
      - Garden book - Kate Horsford, 1886-1900 (Box 116, Folder 1)
      - Sylvester Manor landscape gardening, 1890-1901 (Box 116, Folder 2)
      - Horsford Gardening book with scrap notes, 1902-1913 (Box 116, Folder 3)
      - Garden Book - Katharine Horsford, 1907-1920 (Box 116, Folder 4)
      - Printed books, notes including history of the garden at Sylvester Manor by Cornelia Horsford, 1916, 1921, undated (Box 116, Folder 5)
      - Gardening book and correspondence, 1915, 1920, 1921 (Box 116, Folder 6)
      - Garden Book 1920 (Box 116, Folder 7)
      - Notes removed from front cover of Garden Book, 1925-1926, undated (Box 116, Folder 8)
      - Gardening book, 1915-1931 (Box 116, Folder 9)
      - Gardening notes, correspondence, clippings removed from Gardening book front cover, 1931-1933 (Box 116, Folder 10)
      - Gardening notes, correspondence from Gardening book back cover, 1935, undated (Box 116, Folder 11)
      - Memorandum book and pocket guide, 1910-1930 (Box 117, Folder 1)
      - Calling card - "Sent with Delphiniuns", undated (Box 117, Folder 2)
    - Subseries 8: Visual Materials
      - Hand-painted placecard for Mrs. Horsford with signatures from Richard Dana, Henry W. Longfellow, 1877 (Box 117, Folder 3)
      - Pencil sketch "A Rock", 1879 July 4 (Box 117, Folder 4)
      - Copies of 17th and 18th Century portraits, circa 1884 (?) (Box 117, Folder 5)
      - Engraving prints of Sylvester Manor, same as bookplates, signed Edmund H. Garrett, 1916 (Box 117, Folder 6)
      - Framed engraving of Pres. John Tyler, undated (Box 117, Folder 7)
      - Design sketch, undated (Box 117, Folder 8)
      - Prints - Dutch House in New Amsterdam, undated (Box 117, Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous engraving prints, undated (Box 117, Folder 10)
      - Horsford - engravings of politicians - John C. Calhoun and James Buchanan, undated (Box 117, Folder 11)
      - Sketch of windmill, undated (Box 117, Folder 12)
      - Sylvester Manor watercolor and poem by Sir Richard Jebb printed on cards, undated (Box 117, Folder 13)
      - Pressed butterfly, undated (Box 117, Folder 14)
      - Horsford Sylvester Manor, undated (Box 117, Folder 15)
      - Hand-drawn plan of Sylvester Manor grounds, undated (Box 117, Folder 16)
      - Unused color postcard of Sylvester Manor, undated (Box 117, Folder 17)
      - Sketch of boxwoods and axial pathways of garden, undated (Box 117, Folder 18)
      - Pencil sketch of face, undated (Box 117, Folder 19)
      - Sketch of Scandanavian (?) hut, undated (Box 117, Folder 20)
      - Sylvester manor postcards, undated (Box 117, Folder 21)
      - Sketch of girl with practice penmanship, possibly by Mary L. Gardiner, undated (Box 117, Folder 22)
      - Card with flower, undated (Box 117, Folder 23)
      - Watercolor of Cambridge house ?, undated (Box 117, Folder 24)
      - Watercolor painting of building on river, undated (Box 117, Folder 25)
      - New national opera house box engraving, undated (Box 117, Folder 26)
      - Print of William and Mary College - note from E.N. Horsford, Sylvester Manor evidently modelled after pictured building, undated (Box 117, Folder 27)
      - Packet of bookplates with prints of engravings by Edmund Garrett; prints of paintings of Mary and Margaret Sylvester from Met, undated (Box 117, Folder 28)
      - Bookplate image of Sylvester Manor with envelope, undated (Box 117, Folder 29)
      - Watercolor map of Great Britain and Ireland, undated (Box 117, Folder 30)
      - Postcard of Sigma Phi House in Williamstown, MA, undated (Box 117, Folder 31)
      - Image of unknown English Church, undated (Box 117, Folder 32)
      - Miscellaneous engraving and prints, undated (Box 117, Folder 33)
      - Tourist prints of European cities and sights, undated (Box 117, Folder 34)
      - Sketch, engraving, Seaview House, undated (Box 117, Folder 35)
      - Images for stained glass, undated (Box 117, Folder 36)
      - Engraving print [large bookplate?] - "Gardens at Sylvester Manor", undated (Box 117, Folder 37)
      - Engravings - Inez de la Cruz and boy, undated (Box 117, Folder 38)
      - Portrait engraving of John Hancock, undated (Box 117, Folder 39)
        Framed with invitation card, Box 5 Folder 11.
  - Horsford: Oversize
    - Oversize Series A Subseries 1: Correspondence
      - Joseph L. Chester, 1839 (Box 145, Folder 1)
      - Eliza Horsford, 1835, 1839, undated (Box 145, Folder 2)
      - Eliza Horsford and M.C. Horsford, 1839 (Box 145, Folder 4)
      - Julia Horsford, Maria Horsford and M.C. Horsford, 1839 (Box 145, Folder 6)
      - Laura Horsford and M.C. Horsford, 1839 (Box 145, Folder 6)
      - Eliza Horsford and Laura Horsford, 1840 (Box 145, Folder 3)
    - Oversize Series A Subseries 2: Financial
      - Farm ledger, 1890 (Box 145, Folder 7)
    - Oversize Series A Subseries 3: Shelter Island and Cambridge
      - Maps, Plans and Advertisements for Shelter Island Park, 1874 (Map-case Map-case 4.B, Folder 7)
      - Farm mortgate - Eben N. Horsford et al, 1872, 1880 (Box 145, Folder 9)
      - Deeds for property in Cambridge - 34 Newbury Street, and property of Theodore H. Leavey, 1839, 1882 (Box 145, Folder 8)
      - Lot map of Shelter Island, undated (Box 145, Folder 10)
      - "Shelter Island Parks - A New Watering Place" with notice of small farms for sale by Professor E.N. Horsford 1 of 2, undated (Box 145, Folder 11)
      - "Shelter Island Parks - A New Watering Place" with notice of small farms for sale by E.N. Horsford 2 of 2, undated (Box 145, Folder 12)
        Scrapbook of clippings